SAMANTHA JUNE CALVERT

|Researcher| Meticulous | Organized | Problem-solver | Collaborative |

Mobile: 082 582 0880 | Email: samanthajune9.calvert@gmail.com | Gender: Female

Nationality: South African | Languages: English and Afrikaans

Residential Area: Mamre, Cape Town

Github: https://github.com/Samantha-June?tab=repositories

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Samantha Calvert is a passionate researcher with a curious mindset. Having worked in both academia and government, she displays professionalism in her day-to-day life.

Some of her strongest skills are monitoring and evaluating projects, research, analysis, attention to detail, teamwork, customer-service, relationship-building, report and research writing.

Possessing a background of coding, her long-term goal is becoming a Data Scientist, and she is currently pursuing data analysis and software development to become more proficient with the analyses of data and information.

TECH STACK

- •HTML •CSS •JavaScript •React is •Node is •Python •Flexbox •Github •Netlify •Low-no code •Mentimeter
- •CANVA •Use cases •Data analysis •Data Visualization •Visual Studio Code •Skype •Discord •Slack
- Microsoft TeamsZoom

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- ·Microsoft Office 365 (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) ·Detail-oriented ·Data entry ·Research ·Report writing
- •Customer-oriented •Monitoring and evaluation •Administration •Multi-task •Organized •Systems thinker
- •Empathetic •Critical thinker •Problem-solving •Reliable •Interpersonal •Communication

EDUCATION | QUALIFICATIONS

- Master of Development Studies (University of the Western Cape) 2018-2022 <u>Average:</u> 70%
 Thesis Title: Food Insecurity amongst Seasonal Women Farm Workers in Cape Winelands District
- Bachelor of Commerce (Honours): Finance (University of the Western Cape) 2017 Average: 70%
- Bachelor of Commerce: Economics & Finance (University of the Western Cape) 2014-2016 Average: 69%
- Matriculated: Robinvale High School, Atlantis, Western Cape 2006.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Golden Key International Honour Society 2022
- Food Systems Programme Recognition Award
- NRF scholarship recipient 2017 2019
- Truworths Bursary 2015
- UWC Merit Awards 2015
- ATKV Olympics Afrikaans 71% 2006
- Afrikaans 2nd Language HG B: Certificate of Merit 2006
- Small Business Management & Entrepreneurship N3 2005
- English 1st Language HG B: Certificate of Merit 2005
- Economics SG B: Certificate of Merit 2004

TRAINING COURSES

- CapaCiTi Digital Career Accelerator (current) HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React js, Node js, Python
- SheCodes Foundation (current) API, Git, Hosting, AI
- Udemy (current) Tableau
- GirlCode Bootcamp (August October 2023) Python, Web development, Object-oriented programming (OOP), HTML, CSS, Github
- Brainnest Data Analysis Training Program (May 2022) Statistical data analysis

- Mozisha International Limited Data Analytics Accelerator Programme (February April 2022) Excel data cleaning, SQL and Power BI
- Assertiveness skills 2021
- Presentation skills 2021

WORK EXPERIENCE

Thesis editor | Freelance January – June 2023

Edited a thesis and did bibliography checks.

Researcher (full-time) | City of Cape Town, Future Planning and Resilience Directorate, Resilience Department

August 2019 – August 2022

Strategy and implementation planning

- Engaged 15+ internal departments and 10+ external organizations to obtain and distribute information for development challenges whilst establishing collaboration and partnerships.
 - Research included gender-based violence, mental health, diversionary programmes, neighbourhood safety, be-a-buddy, climate change, trauma, food insecurity, sustainable food systems and women and girl's inequalities and resilience.
- Drafted proposals, memos and reports.
- Drafted minutes of meeting.
- Captured food system research projects for Cape Town.
- Presented research to a food system working group for feedback and knowledge sharing.
- Set up and participated in resilience workshops.
- Attended Women in Leadership (WIL) workshops advocating for the empowerment of women in the workplace.
- Created graphs to record flows, relationships and gaps for intervention and mapped stakeholders.
 - Visualization tool used Draw.io
- Collated, updated and monitored 93 City food-related projects as well as Cape Town's Resilience Strategy.
- Produced feedback forms and followed up on responses.
- Assisted with the development and mitigation of shock scenarios and existing stresses to Cape Town's food system.
- Performed ad hoc research to support stakeholder research and their projects.
- Arranged transport to Site visits.
- Engaged with locals in different communities by identifying challenges to their livelihoods in order to improve their food systems.
- Provided input to policies and strategies.
- Narrated City of Cape Town's project contribution towards Sustainable Development Goal 2: Zero Hunger
- Cleaned and organized databases SharePoint and excel.
 - SharePoint and Google (cloud based) Created folders, stored, edited and shared resources making it easier for retrieval.
 - Excel database Data was cleaned and studied for missing values, duplications, spelling and grammatical errors through the filter function and conditional formatting.

Research Administrative Assistant (Work-study) | University of the Western Cape, EMS - Institute for Social Development (ISD)

February 2018 - July 2019

- Assisted post-graduate students with applications and registrations.
- Compiled, updated, organized and filed thesis proposals and other documentation manually and electronically.
- Helped HOD and lecturers with CAM marks and analysis of student performance.
- Amended and updated Research Agendas.

- Performed daily administrative functions.
- Set up venues for lectures and special events.

Work Experience Internship | Western Cape Government, Provincial Treasury October 2017 (1 week)

Inserted excel formulas to determine budget allocation expenditures for upcoming years.

Business Management & Marketing Management Tutor | University of the Western Cape, EMS - School of Business & Finance (SBF)

[August 2016 - October 2016] [March 2016 - June 2016]

- Administered 15+ students' subject material and presented instructions to class activities.
- Facilitated conversations related to subject matter.
- Captured tutorial attendance and marked scripts.
- Arranged student consultations and provided motivation to complete course.

Vacation work (intern) | Western Cape Tourism, Trade and Investment Promotion Agency (WESGRO)

June 2016 - July 2016 (2 weeks)

- Updated central business information and sorted business cards.
- Attended entrepreneurship meetings with clients.

Library Administrative Assistant (Work-study) | University of the Western Cape, School of Government (SOG)

February 2015 - November 2015

- Provided post-graduate students with relevant research material for assignments and theses.
- Referred students to relevant main library section for more research materials.
- Organized book cataloguing.

PROJECTS

CapaCiti (current): Tourism website

- Created a tourism website which allows visitors to book packages in two popular provinces in South Africa.

GirlCode Hackathon (October 2023): Gaming review app

- Created a low-no code Video Game review app for parents to make informed decisions when getting a video game for their children.

GirlCode Bootcamp (August 2023)

- Created my first career development webpages.

City of Cape Town (April 2021 – August 2022): Research Agenda Matrix

 Captured all food system research projects in the city and identified further research and data gaps for government and partners in academia to investigate.

City of Cape Town (March 2021 – May 2021): Trauma-informed training project – Langa & Elsies River community

- Served as a research assistant to the Policy and Strategy Research branch.
- Observed participant behaviours' and interviewed 2 community leaders for the evaluation of a traumainformed training project.

City of Cape Town (September 2019 – October 2020): Food Systems Programme

- Developed a Food Systems Programme for Cape Town and established 30 broad food actions that the City is currently emerged in or plan to embark on to improve the food system.

- Actions fell under specific themes such as food governance, food resilience, food production, food environments, food & health and food economy.

University of the Western Cape (July 2018 - October 2018): Lavender Hill Project: Funding Proposal

- Identified social challenges and created a funding proposal for a hypothetical Non-Profit Organization for projects on youth skills, leadership and development.

University of the Western Cape (July 2017 - October 2017): Translator and Data Capturer

- Translated, captured and analyzed food insecurity of seasonal farm women survey responses on SPSS to assist with the motivation of an adult seasonal social grant.
- Worked in a team to ensure data and responses were captured accurately.
- Liaised with colleague on data gaps and errors discovered during data collection.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Unilever Archives and Records Management Volunteer (Oct – Nov 2023)

Transcribed and archived historical letters pertaining to the company in a catalogued database.

Orion Church International (2023) – Food Pantry Assistant

Sourced, managed and distributed food parcels to needy congregants.

- Orion Church International (2023) Sunday School Teacher
 - Taught the Bible, cared for and played with children.
 - Budgeted for events and assisted with plays.
- ICLEI AFRICA (August & September 2021) Food, Water & Energy Nexus Training Programme
 - Training involved knowledge sharing about climate change impacts on food, water and energy.
 - Developed a heatwave proposal to Cape Town's food system.
- South African Food & Farming Trust (June 2020 October 2020; May 2021 October 2021) –
 Food Dialogues Volunteer Coordinator
 - Interviewed an array of expert speakers across the food and health industry and summarized the verbal responses to inform the Food Dialogues Report released on World Food Day on 16 October 2020.
 - Provided support with interviewers' profiles and video soundbite quotes.
- Tupperware representative (2019 2021)
- University of the Western Cape (July 2017 September 2017) International Food Fair Volunteer Planner (to highlight the food insecurity problem on campus)
 - Assisted with planning, coordinating and facilitating an annual International Food Fair.
 - Prepared and served traditional South African dishes.
- University of the Western Cape (June 2016 July 2016) Young Investor Programme Member Undertook a company analysis and participated in monthly presentations.

REFERENCES

Mrs. Shehnaz Cassim Moosa Senior Resilience Analyst Resilience Department, City of Cape Town

<u>Shehnaz.CassimMoosa@capetown.gov.za</u>

Cell: 072 821 5371

Mr. Brandon September
Education Digital mentor
CapaCiti_Digital Career Accelerator
Brandon.September@capaciti.org.za

Cell: 079 477 0660